NYSUT President's Office Files. 6174/001
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
- Series Presidents files: Subseries 2
  - New York Special Olympics Board of Directors, 1995 (Box 53, Folder 71)
    October 8, 1995. Minutes of Executive Committee meeting of September 15-16, 1995; NYSO Celebrity Cabaret in honor of the 25th Anniversary Celebration: Outline of Event; committee reports; correspondence
  - New York Special Olympics Board of Directors, 1995 (Box 53, Folder 72)
    December 1-2, 1995. President/CEO report on current and recently completed projects; memo re direct marketing; minutes of October 7 Executive Committee meeting; minutes of September 15 Planning Committee meeting; Special Olympics Three-Year Plan, January 1, 1995, through December 31, 1997; personal information re candidates for Board of Directors; calendar of events for 1996
  - New York Special Olympics Development Committee, 1996 (Box 53, Folder 73)
    1997 Steering Committee meeting agenda; minutes of May 19, 1994, meeting of NYSO Task Force on Development; action plans; spreadsheet of events; memo to CEO, president, chairman of the board, and Tony Bifaro as member of Executive Committee, pointing out errors involving Cabaret/25th Anniversary event, December 6, 1995; 1996 Sponsorship Proposal; correspondence
  - New York Special Olympics Awards, 1995-1996 (Box 53, Folder 74)
    Nomination forms for awards; acceptance speech for Dorothy Buehring Phillips Award; letter informing NYSUT assistant to the president Tony Bifaro that he had been selected to receive the Dorothy Buehring Phillips Award, February 12, 1996
  - New York Special Olympics Executive Committee, 1996 (Box 53, Folder 75)
    January 26-27, 1996. 1996 Sports Handbook; New York Special Olympics 25th Anniversary Commemorative Book: Silver Celebration Celebrating 25 Years of Champions; financial statements; draft Games and Training Committee roles and responsibilities; draft Guidelines for a Quality Program; president's performance review; correspondence re upcoming meetings
  - New York Special Olympics Budget, 1996 (Box 53, Folder 76)
    Spreadsheets; memos re 1996 approved budget
  - New York Special Olympics Summer Games, 1996 (Box 53, Folder 77)
    June 13-16, 1996. Agreement between University at Albany (SUNY) and New York Special Olympics, Inc., for 1996 New York Special Olympics Summer Games; certificate of insurance; correspondence with Tony Bifaro re sponsorship; 1996 Sponsorship Proposal; schedule of events; souvenir program; list of sponsors; Opening Ceremonies Script and related material for Tony Bifaro
  - New York Special Olympics Board of Directors, 1996 (Box 53, Folder 78)
    Materials for Board of Directors meeting, including committee reports and Three-Year Plan through December 31, 1997
  - Special Olympics World Games, 1997 (Box 53, Folder 79)
    Printed brochures; fact sheets
  - Political Endorsement Conference, 1994 (Box 54, Folder 1)
    August 8-10, 1994. NYSUT press release announcing endorsement of Mario Cuomo for governor, August 10, 1994; conference agenda
  - AFT QuEST, 1995 (Box 54, Folder 2)
    July 27-30, 1995. AFT department reports, prepared for the AFT Executive Council Meeting, July 27, 1995; summary of actions of the AFT Executive Committee, July 26, 1995; printed AFT QuEST '95 Program, "Higher Stakes, Higher Standards: Designing Schools Where Students Achieve"; conference call from Al Shanker, discussing theme, with attached descriptive materials
  - School-to-Work Advisory Committee, 1994 (Box 54, Folder 3)
    List of advisory committee members; descriptions of role of advisory committee
  - School-to-Work Advisory Committee, 1994 (Box 54, Folder 4)
    December 21, 1994. Agenda for meeting of December 21, 1994; summaries of meetings of August 2, 3, and 9, 1994; summary of results of meeting of January 5, 1995; summary of decisions at School-to-Work retreat, October 20, 1994; development grant status report by area of activity; list of questions re local partnership funding; description of School-to-Work Resource Center; meeting reminders from the State of New York Job Training Partnership Council
  - School-to-Work Regional Advisory Committee, 1994-1995 (Box 54, Folder 5)
    List of concerns raised at Mohawk Valley Regional Advisory Committee meeting, January 19, 1995; recommendations for regional advisory committee functions; proposed list of required and recommended partnership members; New York State AFL-CIO School-to-Work Transition Guide for Labor Representatives; list of members of Capital Region School-to-Work Advisory Committee; memo to NYSUT assistant to the president Tony Bifaro describing School-to-Work Opportunities Act meeting, with attached materials, November 30, 1994; correspondence from State Education Department re grant program
  - School-to-Work Advisory Council, 1995 (Box 54, Folder 6)
    May 31, 1995. Meeting agenda; meeting summary; list of members; position paper addressed to Rep. William Goodling, May 1995; memo to Toni Cortese, Tony Bifaro, and Chuck Santelli updating on federal school-to-work legislation, activities of School-to-Work Advisory Council, June 5, 1995
  - School-to-Work Advisory Council, 1995 (Box 54, Folder 7)
    September 22, 1995. Meeting minutes; meeting agendas; brochure, "New York State Tech Prep, the successful school-to-work model"; document, "New York State Tech Prep Works: A Successful School-to-Work Transition Program"; outline of recommended process for allocation of funding for local partnerships; memo from the NYS Job Training Partnership Council re waiver requests under federal School-to-Work Opportunities Act, September 22, 1995; press release from U.S. Department of Education/Department of Labor School to Work Opportunities program, "Clinton Administration Announces $161 Million in School-to-Work Grants for 27 States," September 19, 1995; letter to Oklahoma governor Frank Keating from Miss Oklahoma, Shawntel Smith, promoting the School-to-Work program, June 13, 1995; brochure by State University of New York, aimed at high school students, "Now is the time! Plan a successful future," re importance of taking Regents-level courses, noting Tech Prep as an option, spring 1995; draft Notice of Intent from State Education Department re application process for funding local partnerships under year two of the federal School-to-Work Opportunities Act, including fact sheet and list of currently funded local partnerships, September 18; memo to Toni Cortese, Tony Bifaro, and Chuck Santelli, "Report on School-to-Work Subcommittee on Local Partnerships: June 21, 1995"; letter from the Business Council of New York State, Inc., to executive director of New York State Association of Counties, re request by School-to-Work Advisory Council to change geographic boundaries of service delivery areas to larger regions, June 27, 1995; materials for July 19 meeting; memo from State Education Department to advisory council members re eligibility of grants to parochial and other nonpublic schools, July 13, 1995; draft Request for Proposals (RFP) for New York State School-to-Work Opportunities Local Partnership Competitive Incentive Grants, sent to advisory committee from State Education Department, July 14, 1995
  - School-to-Work Advisory Council, 1995 (Box 54, Folder 8)
    March 29-30, 1995. Tentative agenda and notice of meeting of March 29 and 30; list of Capital District School-to-Work planning grant submissions
  - School-to-Work Advisory Council, 1996 (Box 54, Folder 9)
    January-May, 1996. Memo from State Education Department to advisory council, polling members re change in name of program to School-to-Careers, with affirmative vote by Tony Bifaro, January 25, 1996; notice for May 16, 1996, meeting; letter from state Commissioner of Labor John E. Sweeney to Tony Bifaro, inviting him to New York City Job and Career Center, Inc., reception and Q&A session, February 15, 1996
  - School-to-Work Advisory Council, 1996 (Box 54, Folder 10)
    January 18, 1996. Draft agenda; highlights of meeting of November 15, 1995; confidential draft spreadsheet re disposition of School-to-Work Resource Center activities, and cover letter to advisory committee from State Education Department, January 18; descriptions of activities/program grantees: Assessment of Initial Mastery (A.I.M. - SUNYA), staff development (SUNYA), career counseling (SUNYA), Summer Institute (SUNYA), work-based activities (Erie I), teacher prep (SUNYA), school-based curricula (Syracuse University)
  - School-to-Work Advisory Council, 1996 (Box 54, Folder 11)
    June 5-6, 1996. Draft agenda; grantee progress report for January 1 - March 31 quarter; New York State Department of Labor/New York Association of Training and Employment Professionals Report to the Governor: Policy Framework for New York's Workforce Development System, February 1996; invitation to attend national School-to-Work Institute "Grand Prix," May 29, 1996; Partnership Self-Assessment: New York State School-to-Work, created by Westchester Institute for Human Services Research, Inc.; proposal to provide School-to-Work outreach to special needs populations, from New York State Division for Youth, Bureau of Education and Employment Services (BEES), June 3, 1996; letter to State Education Department coordinator for Workforce Prep & Continuing Education from national School-to-Work office, critiquing New York implementation of program, lack of regional structure, May 6, 1996; brochure, "Board of Regents and State Education Department Draft Strategic Plan: Are we on the right track? Tell us "; School-to-Work Implementation Grant (Year One) 10/01/94 - 9/30/96 Fiscal Status Report as of May 22, 1996
  - School-to-Work Advisory Council, 1996 (Box 54, Folder 12)
    July 19, 1996. Meeting announcement and agenda; New York State School-to-Work Final Performance Report FY 1995-96 and Three Year Continuation Application FY 1996-97; Attachment A, Staff and Curriculum Development Plan; draft bylaws; draft amendment to the bylaws; New York State American Federation of Labor and Congress of Industrial Organization (AFL-CIO) Outreach & Technical Assistance to Organized Labor: Proposal to the State Education Department for Participation in School-to-Work
  - School-to-Work Advisory Council, 1996 (Box 54, Folder 13)
    September 12, 1996. Meeting agenda; list of members; bar graphs showing school district participation in local School-to-Work partnerships; New York State School-to-Work Final Performance Report FY 1995-96 and Three Year Continuation Application FY 1996-97; draft bylaws; Report of the Advisory Council for School-to-Work Opportunities to the U.S. Departments of Education and Labor, March 28-29, 1996, with cover transmittal letter; brochure and flyer, Preparing Students for Technological Society: An Evening with Dr. Willard R. Daggett, director, International Center for Leadership in Education, October 16, 1996
  - School-to-Work Advisory Council, 1996 (Box 54, Folder 14)
    November 14, 1996. Meeting notice and response form; program/agenda; summary of meeting of September 12
  - School-to-Work Advisory Council, 1997 (Box 54, Folder 15)
    May 14, 1997. Agenda; newsletters from the Private Industry Council, the Business Council of New York State, Inc.; schedule for public forums with State Education Commissioner Richard Mills re High School Graduation Requirements: The Whole Picture; summary of March 19 meeting
  - School-to-Work Career Pathways, 1992-1994 (Box 54, Folder 16)
    Printed report to the governor, "Education That Works: Creating Career Pathways for New York State Youth," September 1992; letter from NYSUT president Tom Hobart to local presidents, inviting them to regional hearings on the report, September 28, 1992; Department of Labor publication, "Licensed Occupations of the Northeast"; Federal Register publication of School-to-Work Opportunities State Implementation Grants Program, February 3, 1994
  - School-to-Work Career Pathways, 1993 (Box 54, Folder 17)
    February 1, 1993. "Gateway: New York's Employment Connection," by Gov. Mario Cuomo, November/December 1992 issue of Directions; handwritten notes; revised draft, "Elements of a New Regents Diploma System," 12/8/92; critique of report to governor, "Education That Works: Creating Career Pathways for New York State Youth," by the School/Industry Advisory Board of the Smithtown Central School District, December 21, 1992; copy of report with handwritten edits by the Curriculum and Instruction Committee of the NYS Council of School Superintendents, with an apologetic cover letter from the assistant director, January 20, 1993
  - School-to-Work Career Pathways Roundtable, 1992 (Box 54, Folder 18)
    December 9, 1992. Printed report to the governor, "Education That Works: Creating Career Pathways for New York State Youth," September 1992; memo to Board of Regents, "Summary of Issues Raised at Career Pathways Regional Forums," December 3, 1992; recommendations and speaking points for Career Pathways (unattributed); State Education Department publication, "A New Compact for Learning: Improving Public Elementary, Middle, and Secondary Education Results in the 1990s (includes 1991 revised Regents goals)"
  - School-to-Work Career Majors Subcommittee, Workforce Prep Pilot Program, 1994 (Box 54, Folder 19)
    April 26, 1994. Tentative agenda for Workforce Preparation Advisory Committee meeting, April 26, 1994; summary of proposal by Career Majors Subcommittee for Advisory Committee action; draft agenda for 10/20/94 Career Majors meeting; summary of May 19, 1994, meeting; memo with attached report, "Career Major Options: A Report for the Workforce Preparation Committee," April 26, 1994; "Career Majors: A Report prepared by the NYS Occupational Education Association," February 14, 1994
  - The State of Public Education in Erie County (Erie County Leadership Forum), 1995 (Box 54, Folder 20)
    February 25, 1995. Agenda; NYSUT flyers, "What we believe about teachers' salaries; public school alternatives; school-to-work transition; merit pay; school reform; testing; placement of students with disabilities; school boards"; NYSUT memoranda, "Preliminary Analysis of the Executive Budget, K-12; NYC; Higher Education Budgets" February 2, 1995
  - Take Our Daughters to Work, 1996 (Box 54, Folder 21)
    4/10/96. Flyer from the Ms. Foundation for Women with suggestions for girls and women re Take Our Daughters to Work day; issue of New York Teacher re participation in Take Our Daughters to Work day, April 23, 1996; memos from NYSUT president Tom Hobart to staff, re planned activities for the day, April; opinion column in New York Times opposing Take Our Daughters to Work day, March 31, 1996
  - Take Our Daughters to Work, 1995 (Box 54, Folder 22)
    4/27/95. Memos from NYSUT president Tom Hobart to staff, re planned activities for the day, April; issue of New York Teacher re participation in Take Our Daughters to Work day, April 27, 1995; list of participants; folder of materials from Ms. Foundation for Women re Take Our Daughters to Work day
  - Take Our Daughters to Work Planning Committee, 1995 (Box 54, Folder 23)
    4/13/95. Editorial from Daily/Sunday Gazette (Schenectady, NY) re justification for excluding boys in Take Our Daughters to Work day, April 11, 1995; Employer's Guide for Take Our Daughter to Work day activities, from the Ms. Foundation for Women, 1995; checklist by the foundation for girls and adult participants
  - Teaching as a Career, 1988 (Box 54, Folder 24)
    Booklet by AFT
  - One-with-One NYSUT Mentoring, 1989 (Box 54, Folder 25)
    Draft description, "One-with-One: A NYSUT Mentoring Program for Middle School Students Aspiring to be Teachers, targeted to minority students; State Education Department memo to NYSUT re grant conditions and requirements for minority mentoring program, June 12, 1989; excerpts from description of NYC mentoring program, with handwritten note that mentors are fingerprinted
  - One-with-One Program, 1988-1989 (Box 54, Folder 26)
    Draft description, "One-with-One: A NYSUT Mentoring Program for Middle School Students Aspiring to be Teachers, targeted to minority students; One-with-One Albany Pilot Program timetable; handwritten notes, "Components of a Planned Mentoring Program"; handwritten notes re parental involvement; description, Development of a Mentor Program Parent Education Component; memo from the NYS Job Training Partnership Council re a minority youth teacher mentoring program, May 23, 1988; memo re NYSUT mentoring program, May 17, 1989; letter to Sandra Feldman, president, United Federation of Teachers (UFT), from the Governor's School and Business Alliance Task Force (SABA), re New York State Mentoring Committee and efforts to motivate at-risk students, April 21, 1989; related correspondence
  - Minority Recruitment, 1989 (Box 54, Folder 27)
    Report, "Educating for the Future: A Minority Recruitment Plan for Educators," developed by Ben W. Ellis in conjunction with the Education Committee, Wilmington Branch, NAACP, Brandywine School District, University of Delaware and Delaware State College, June 1989; description of F.A.S.T. Program (Future Academic Scholars Track): An Early Access to Higher Education Program for 6th and 9th Grade Students, administered by the Office of Multicultural and Special Services, Indiana-Perdue University; article reprints; handwritten notes
  - Mentors/ Proteges, 1989 (Box 54, Folder 28)
    "A Guide to New York's Child Protective Services System"; Mandated Reporter Manual, New York State Child Protective Services; mentor candidate interview checklist summary of content and process; correspondence from mentors
  - Mentoring, 1989 (Box 54, Folder 29)
    Bound collection of materials re NYS and NYC mentoring program, newspaper articles, and correspondence
  - Alliance (Newsletter of School and Business Alliance), 1988-1989 (Box 54, Folder 30)
    Newsletter featuring interview with Matilda Cuomo on mentoring, brochure re NYS mentoring program; final agenda for the Mentoring Conference of the Governor's School and Business Alliance and the NYS Mentoring Committee, January 31, 1989; NYS Mentoring Committee update on mentoring; "What Is SABA?" description of the governor's School and Business Alliance; NYC Board of Education Mentoring Program Questions and Answers Fact Sheet; memo from NYS Department of Labor re mentoring as an employment and training component, August 11, 1987; overview of workshops
  - The Two of Us: Handbook for Mentors, 1990-1991 (Box 55, Folder 1)
    Guide published by the Abell Foundation, Inc., Baltimore, Maryland
  - Passing the Torch: Retired Teachers as Mentors, 1987 (Box 55, Folder 2)
    Report published by the Center for Advanced Study in Education (CASE), Graduate School and University Center, City University of New York (CUNY)
  - Choices: A Teen Woman's Journal for Self-Awareness and Personal Planning, 1984-1987 (Box 55, Folder 3)
    Book published by Girls Club of Santa Barbara, 1984, updated 1987
  - Literature on Teaching, n.d. (Box 55, Folder 4)
    "The How to be a Better Student Study Guide"; Teacher Career Recruitment Clearinghouse description and five-year plan, from State Education Department
  - Requests/Orders (Mentoring), 1989 (Box 55, Folder 5)
    Memo requesting book, Teacher Recruitment and Retention, with special emphasis on minority teachers, 1989; other order invoices for mentoring-and minority-related publications, general supplies
  - Training/Journal (Mentoring) c., 1986 (Box 55, Folder 6)
    Handwritten notes
  - Correspondence (Mentoring), 1989-1990 (Box 55, Folder 7)
    Letter from Matilda Cuomo to NYSUT president Tom Hobart re mentoring program, July 17, 1989; letter to NYSUT assistant to the president Tony Bifaro from Cornell vice president Larry Palmer, thanking him for mentoring manual, February 22, 1990, letters from Christina Sullivan, coordinator of NYSUT mentoring program, thanking various parties for feedback on mentoring program
  - Mailings 1, 2, 3, 1989 (Box 55, Folder 8)
    Letters from Hobart to students re interest in teaching as a career
  - Special Olympics, 1990-1991 (Box 55, Folder 9)
    Minutes and agenda of Executive Committee meeting of February 1-2, 1991; minutes of Board of Directors meetings of November 30-December 1 and March 9-10, 1990; agenda for Board of Directors meeting of March 8-9, 1991, annual meeting of June 8, 1990; modified budget items, January 18, 1991; committee reports for Board of Directors meeting of March 8-9, 1991, annual meeting of June 8, 1990; unaudited cash position as of December 31, 1990; second draft of proposed budget for fiscal year 1991-92; third revised proposed budget for 1990-91; revised bylaws as of December 1, 1990, and as of June 8, 1990; memos from Development Committee re distribution of funds for the Run for the Gold program, other issues, February 1, 1991; list of members of Board of Directors; memo re direct marketing efforts for fiscal year 1991; list of activities for 1990 Summer Games; slate of nominees for election to Board of Directors, with biographical descriptions, May 10, 1990; press release re selection of Douglas Single as new president and CEO of Special Olympics International, April 11, 1990; "Proposed Costs for an Extra Day at the Winter Games"; description of Corporate Strategic Planning Council; list of sponsors; revised solicitation figures for 1990 sponsorships, April 24, 1990
  - Special Olympics, 1989-1991 (Box 55, Folder 10)
    Brochure re Run for the Gold, with message of support from NYSUT president Tom Hobart; confidential memo to Board of Directors re workload assessment/position analysis study and recommendation for staffing and reorganization, November 21, 1989; agenda, president's report, and committee reports for Board of Directors meeting of December 1-2, 1989; budget comparisons (approved vs. actual expenditures); list of state committee chairs, revised September 23, 1989; letter from founder and chair Eunice Kennedy Shriver to chair of New York Special Olympics re focus of coming year, with attached remarks by Shriver at the 1989 Special Olympics Conference, and examples of successful funding outreach, August 10, 1989; final report of review of New York Special Olympics, from director of U.S. Chapters to chair of state organization, September 26, 1989; official Special Olympics Style Guide (how to use the Special Olympics logo and other insignia); minutes of Executive Committee meeting of May 5-6, 1989; minutes of Board of Directors meeting of June 9, 1989; memo re personnel policies revision re sick leave, medical coverage, classification of hourly employment, August 22, 1989; press release announcing new executive director of New York Special Olympics, with cover letter to Tony Bifaro requesting publicity by NYSUT, July 10, 1989; confidential memo for file re executive director position, noting strengths and weaknesses of first director, qualities needed in next director; approved budget for 1989-90, with cover memo from Financial Planning Committee; agenda and committee reports for Board of Directors meeting of November 30-December 1, 1990; proposed bylaw amendments; minutes of Executive Committee meeting of October 26-27, 1990; agenda for Executive Committee meeting for April 26-27, 1991; unaudited cash position as of March 31, 1991; first draft of schedule of events for program year July 1, 1991 - July 31, 1992
  - New York Special Olympics Long-Range Planning Committee, 1988-1990 (Box 55, Folder 11)
    New York Special Olympics, Inc., Development Plan; progress report from Planning Committee, re planning goals, March 4, 1991; Organizational Plan, second draft, including staff input, April 6, 1989; earlier draft
  - NYSUT History Project, 1989 (Box 55, Folder 12)